A Guide to Additional George Green Shackelford Papers 1978-1984
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional George Green Shackelford Papers 1978-1984
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
3525-ap
This accession consists of ca. 500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by George Green Shackelford of Blacksburg, Virginia, on June 28, 1984.
Scope and Content Information
This accession consists of items pertaining to the writing, editing, and printing of Collected Papers of the Monticello Association of the Descendants of Thomas Jefferson, Volume II, edited by George Green Shackelford, and published by the Monticello Association, Charlottesville, Virginia, 1984. Included in the collection ar ecorrespondence with publishers, descendants of Thomas Jefferson, and libraries; drafts of chapters, some with corrections and source material; genealogical charts; the setting copy; and various proofs.
Contents List
- Correspondence 1979-1983, n.d. (Box 1)
- Correspondence w/Walker Cowen and James A. Bear, Jr. 1978-1983 (Box 1)
- Correspondence and Source Material re: Craig, Eppes, Shine and Greatham families 1925-1981 (Box 1)
- Correspondence and Source Material re: Thomas Jefferson Eppes 1982 (Box 1)
- Correspondence w/W.E. Loftin, Heritage Printers 1982-1984 (Box 1)
- Correspondence and Source Material re Randolph-Hubard family 1979-1982 (Box 1)
- Correspondence w/Stedman, Coolidge, and McMurdo family members 1980-1984 (Box 1)
- Material re: Ch. V, "Thomas Mann Randolph and Elizabeth Anne Pryor Bankhead" 1978-1983 (Box 1)
- Material re: Ch. VII, "William Stuart Bankhead" 1981-1983 (Box 1)
- Material re: Ch. XI, "Caryanne Nicholas Randolph and Francis Gildart Ruffin" 1978-1983 (Box 1)
- Material re: Ch. XII, "Ellen Wayles Randolph and William Byrd Harrison" 1981 (Box 1)
- Material re: Ch. XIII, "Maria Jefferson Carr Randolph and Charles Mason" 1980-1983 (Box 1)
- Material re: Ch. XV, "Jane Nicholas Randolph and Robert Garlick Hill Kean" 1979-1982 (Box 1)
- Material re: Ch. XVI, "Wilson Cary Nicholas Randolph" 1979 (Box 1)
- Material re: Ch. XIX, "Joseph Randolph and Julia Gardner Coolidge" 1981-1983 (Box 1)
- Material re: Ch. XXI, "Algernon and Mary Lowell Coolidge" 1982 (Box 1)
- Material re: Ch. XXII, "Thomas Jefferson and Mehitable Sullivan Appleton Coolidge" 1978-1981 (Box 1)
- Material re: Ch. XXIII, "Martha Jefferson Trist and John Woolfolk Burke" 1980-1983 (Box 1)
- Material re: Ch. XXVI, "Isaette Carter Randolph and James Leneaus Hubard" 1982-1983 (Box 1)
- Material re: Ch. XXXIV, "Thomas Jefferson and Theodosia Burr Bellamy Eppes" 1978-1983 (Box 2)
- Material re: Ch. XXXVI, "Susan Frances Eppes and John Armstrong Craig" 1982 (Box 2)
- Material re: Ch. XXXVII, "Maria Jefferson Eppes and William Francis Shine" 1979-1981 (Box 2)
- Material re: Ch. XXXVIII, "Nicholas Ware and Susan Branch Bradford Eppes" 1981-1982 (Box 2)
- Material re: Ch. XLI, "Caroline Matilda Eppes and David Shepard Shine" 1981-1983 (Box 2)
- Material re: Ch. XLII, "Biographical Sketches of Deceased Officers of the Monticello Association" 1981-1983 (Box 2)
- Setting Copy [1983] (Box 2)
  (3 folders)
- Title page and Table of Contents 1984 (Box 2)
- Galey Proof 1984 (Box 2)
- Revised Pages 1984 Jan (Box 2)
- Revised pages 1984 Mar (Box 2)
- Gatherings 1984 Apr (Box 3)
  (2 folders)
- Genealogical Charts [1983-1984] (Box 3)